TSMC is historically a low-vol, very
steady, high-quality company.
But, relative to other AI stocks, it's
still very cheap, especially
>> You just said it is still not as
expensive?
>> By a portfolio, I would definitely put
some money, if not a higher waiting,
into TSMC.
>> Whenever there's an earthquake, all the
engineers, they don't go to their kids
or their wives, they head straight back
to their companies.
>> So, are you talking about just Taiwan or
are you talking
>> Taiwan, Taiwan.
>> But, it's not like Americans don't work
hard.
>> President Trump said, "We want 50% of
chips made in the USA."
>> How long can the company sustain its
technological edge? Cuz that's the
thesis here, that nobody can do what
they do, at least for now.
>> Pleased to welcome back to the show John
Wu at Consensus Miami. John is the
president of Ava Labs, and prior to Ava
Labs, he was a tech investor for many
years on Wall Street,
at his own fund, and prior to that,
Kingdon Capital as a portfolio manager.
We're happy to have him on the show to
talk about the future of tech investing
and blockchain investing. Welcome to the
show,
John.
>> David, it's a pleasure. Always nice to
see you.
>> And joining me today is Bonnie.
>> Bonnie Che. Um off camera, we were just
talking about TSMC. So, I'm a huge
investor. I Not a huge investor, I'm a a
huge portion of my portfolio.
Sorry.
>> Whale TSMC whale right here.
>> Because I've been holding it for the
longest time, and I'm very passionate
about this. So,
you just said it is still not as
expensive?
>> So, I know people who've invested in
TSMC. As David said, I was a
professional tech investor for a long
time,
and I know not only professional hedge
fund investors, venture people invest in
this stuff, and as well as operators in
all of these companies. And TSMC is
historically a low-ball, very steady,
high-quality company.
But and and the valuation is very fair,
usually.
Relative to itself, it's probably more
expensive because it sits in such an
important place, and they have They're
the best of what they do.
But, relative to other AI stocks, it's
still very cheap, especially considering
the growth rates.
>> Is it because of the location?
>> I think there's a little discount for
the location as, you know, we talked
about off camera, the proximity to
China.
Um but also, I think also, in general,
like people are not um
aware of this company as much as they
would if they were a US company.
They're, you know, US companies just get
naturally more publicity.
>> So, let's say if I have the same amount
of money and two equal company, would
you go for the US market?
>> All right, so I'm I'm going to put a
disclaimer out there. I used to be a
investor. Now, I am a passionate
follower, and I have friends who still
invest, and I keep up with the space.
So, this is not for investing advice.
So, if I had
a portfolio, I would definitely put some
money, if not
a higher weighting, into TSMC.
>> Okay.
>> And it's not just TSMC. There There's a
lot of other companies related in the AI
supply chain in Taiwan.
A lot of memory companies in Korea.
There's also Tokyo Electron in Japan.
Asia is very good at the uh hardware and
the electrical engineering layer of AI,
which is really where a lot of the
things that are in scarcity
are. So, there's a lot of good things to
look at in Asia, companies I should say,
and TSMC is probably um at the very top
of that list.
>> But, would you bet on US companies
getting bought
or at least invested in by the
government, which is exactly what
happened with Intel, and went up double
digits in a few trading sessions. I'm
not saying it will happen, but you know,
just to compare East versus West here,
isn't that a factor you should consider?
>> Well, I mean,
as an American first, um I I I hope
Intel can create the sophistication in
their foundry business and have uh jobs
in the US. Um but they are still far
away. Intel's very good also at making
CPUs. And part of the reason why Intel's
up, it's not just because of the good
management and because they're trying to
create uh foundry level type success in
the US, but it's also because there's a
scarcity in CPUs with the agentic world
coming. So, I think you would own Intel
for various reasons, not just because
the US has a stake in it. But that
doesn't hurt, by the way.
>> Okay.
>> I was at Mar-a-Lago a couple weeks ago,
and President Trump said, "We want 50%
of chips made in the USA."
>> Listen,
there's nothing wrong with uh the
president of the United States
>> Of course.
>> wanting jobs and manufacturing coming to
the US. I think that's a great thing. Um
he is very consistent with that theme.
And he's willing to support US
companies. Like I said to David just
now, it's not a bad thing.
>> But I I I would just like to know your
stance on if that is possible.
>> Possible in what sense?
>> As in, okay, in Asia, whenever there's
an earthquake, all the engineers, they
don't go to their kids or their wives.
They head straight back to their
companies.
To protect the chips.
>> Are you talking about
>> Taiwan. Taiwan.
>> Well, that happens all Asia. I mean,
there's a word in Japan for uh uh dying
at your desk from overwork, and that's
actually a very noble way to die as
opposed to get hit by a bus.
>> know about that. Okay.
>> There is a word for that. Trust me,
there is, okay? I
Everyone appreciates the hard work ethic
of um you know, uh
the Asian society and the culture, you
>> know, but you're it's not like Americans
don't work hard either. And there's a
you know, what Americans have is a
slightly different culture. They have a
very entrepreneurial culture. They're a
little bit more risk-taking. So, I think
if you can if I were to build a company
and I did, you know, I will labs
you know, in the founding days we were
10 people in the room all Cornell
engineers and some a lot of them were
Asian hard work ethic.
It didn't matter. We were all hard
working and we were very entrepreneurial
at the same time. So, if you can blend
those two things together, that's the
ideal scenario.
>> I have a question for both of you just
on TSMC before I move on. How long can
the company sustain its technological
edge? Is that cuz that's the thesis here
that nobody can do what they do at least
for now.
>> So, they it's unfortunate that the tech
cycles, when I started investing in tech
cycles were longer.
Tech cycles and the economic cycles are
far shorter.
So, unfortunately, one of the you can
you can say that same thing for Nvidia,
for AMD, for anyone else. Unfortunately,
the reality of the world we live in in
technology today in 2026 is that
consistent and constant innovation can
be an edge and the only edge. Even in
you know,
quant trading firms, okay? These quant
models have a half-life that gets
shorter and shorter. This is why some of
these firms have a gazillion PhDs
because new models have to come out.
It's constant innovation.
In the end, it produces good results
hopefully for society, but the people
working will be working very hard and
has
have to be constantly thinking about new
things.
>> I appreciate that insight. How would you
design your portfolio now?
Are we talking about AI, energy,
safe stock how would you
>> Well, there'll be Listen, if I were in
my professional seat
>> Mhm. Mhm.
>> I would be as a professional There's a
professional portfolio and there's the
individual portfolio.
Like for a person who has a job
day-to-day that's not invested
>> Let's do that first.
>> Okay, but that person, I think this is a
super exciting time. It reminds me of
the internet days. If you can
find a port folio, you're going to get
some of them wrong. But if you can find
the Amazon and the Google and um I guess
Nvidia
of back in the day today
and and as an individual, you can just
with you you don't have to deal with the
day-to-day volatility. If you can find a
portfolio of potentially the best in
various parts of the AI world going
forward
you just sit with them hold it for a
while. So, it's a great and very
exciting time. Imagine if you were you
know
um
25 years ago when you know you probably
got a few of them wrong, but if you
identify Google, Netflix, and Amazon,
just hold it and don't worry about it
the ups and downs.
>> Tom Lee
>> Talk about the professional portfolio.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Sorry. Yeah, professional portfolio
people.
>> Professional portfolio people now are
unbelievable. Let's talk about the
discretionary portfolio people, not the
quants.
They have been very good at identifying
each bottleneck and this is why you're
seeing all of a sudden you're going from
Nvidia alone
to networking. Not just networking, it
becomes, you know, photonics and then it
becomes like memory, you know, Micron,
SK Hynix in Korea. You're talking about
basically
different bottlenecks and they keep
finding the next bottleneck and getting
ahead of that. This is why you're
getting you see these super spikes. Um
Micron's a perfect example. Like Micron
was supposed to be a cyclical
a slow memory business. On a PE basis
it's still cheap, but people don't know
how long it can last, but yet the stock
looks like it should be trading with no
earnings and yet it's trading I think
less than 10 times um next year's
earnings.
>> What I heard is Micron started on
Reddit.
>> Mhm. Well, okay, you're you're going
into a whole different area.
Um
and it's good and bad. I'm torn on this
because you know, when I was a um
professional investor
there was a lot more um call it emphasis
on valuation and emphasis on active
management. People believed that they
can truly generate alpha.
And the percentage of the flow that um
was traded on Nasdaq and and New York
Stock Exchange and other systems was
pretty much the active managers, whether
it's a mutual fund or a hedge fund.
Today it's really quant-driven
ETFs. ETFs are like a big percentage of
the flow now. So, stocks more than ever
are highly correlated and work up and
down together and sometimes nothing to
do with the stock itself, but just
because the weightings of the ETF. You
know, when there was a security scare,
companies like Palantir that are doing
unbelievable because they're in some
sort of software ETF goes down with it
and holds it back. So, the whole Reddit
thing
goes back to the fact that I'm torn
because I love the fact that individual
investors are involved and they feel
like they can participate in this world,
which is great.
But at the same time I do worry that
they over speculate
and then there's less of an emphasis on
valuation because in the long term, and
this is why Warren Buffett has been
great, the power of compounding and and
buying relatively fairly valued
companies
will win out because you don't want to
be in the crazy stocks at the wrong time
and to get really hurt badly. There are
still people, I remember in the internet
age, who bought pets.com or something
and have never recovered. And it's a
shame because if they just
held on to like the 10 or 15 really good
ones or bought an index, they'd be very
well off now.
>> We were talking about the old guard
versus the new in today's age of
investing. So, if you look at the IGV
software for index, for example, it's
down like 27% here to date.
Now, one could argue the market's
pricing and that's the old guard.
Micron, you're just talking about
Micron, for example. Why would anyone,
this is a theoretical question, why
would anyone invest in RAM
companies when right now the innovation
is to reduce RAM
and memory usage in models that when
Turbo Quad came out from Google, for
example,
Micron's stock went it down like 12% in
one day
or 15%?
>> And I think it's like 15% or higher now
than it
>> Yeah, exactly. It recovered, but that
that news brought it down.
>> Which even at that down 12%, it was
already up like 300% whatever. Just to
keep that in mind. Um I I I mean, first
of all, there's a couple things like
just because something is announced
doesn't mean it's going to destroy that
entire industry.
Um
there are a couple from again, I'm an
operator now, all right? It's funny
because like
literally, my team is mostly engineers
and and they're very forward thinking.
They love to play with the new tools and
AI and you know, vibe code and blah blah
blah blah.
I mean, it's almost like we literally
internally, and this is a guy who's just
a smart business guy,
not a coder,
vibe coded our own CRM, customer
relationship management software. Like
we've gotten rid of two different
service providers. We use our own, it's
bespoke. All we need is the database.
And then we have the user of is all
ourselves. So, and then you know, we
were using um
AI and to to do vulnerability testing.
So, it's almost like there was a time
period where like as soon as one of my
guys in engineering comes to me and say,
"Oh, look how cool we we can do this."
Literally, all of a sudden SAS stocks go
down. Security stocks go down.
Uh but so, I you know, if I was still a
hedge fund manager, I'd be shorting all
these things as soon as my guys tell me
something. But, they also tell me things
in more detail. Like, you can't
completely disintermediate a lot of
these things. And a lot of this is way
over hype, in fairness, okay? Sure, if
you're just a UI/UX, you know,
um s- high-level, you know, software
automation tool, that's pretty obvious
it's it's not the sustainability is
going to be difficult. But, you know,
you cannot disintermediate code that,
you know, the this the you know, user
level, you cannot change and write the
code you have from here down.
You know, the core consensus, the core
blockchain, the deep tech code, it's not
being replicated. And in terms of, you
know, what you were talking about with
memory and all that stuff, you're
assuming two things. You're assuming
that in your case, in your specific
example, the memory companies themselves
are not innovating
and knowing what's happening. And the
second thing is you're you're
discounting the business, the you know,
it's a lot more than just tech. It's the
network they have, the supply chain
they're already plugged into. When you
take one piece of tech out, doesn't mean
you can just simply put another piece
in. Because the next piece has to fit in
with everything that already exists in
that tech stack. And that means you have
to replace the whole tech stack if you
want to, you know? That's literally one
of the things that the crypto industry
is learning. You know, there is If you
want to build something from scratch,
there are definitely better ways to do
it.
But, you have legacy in the world, in
tech and rules and everything, that
and and giant businesses that you cannot
fail
by trying whole uh wholehearted
conversion to a new thing. So, you have
to do a step function.
>> What are those?
>> By the way, in the internet age, you'll
probably remember every time there was a
rumor that um
uh Google was going to go into travel,
all of a sudden Expedia and Priceline
and booking.com stocks would crash. This
is 25 years later, they're still like
here and doing better and somehow Google
never was able to get into travel.
>> Uh I want to talk about Bitcoin for a
few minutes.
>> Yeah.
>> $76,000 Bitcoin if it touches if Bitcoin
closes $76,000
we're in a new bull market. This is Tom
Lee at this conference just a few hours
ago. Now, I'm reading a recap of his
speech. You have never in a bear market
Sorry, you have never in a bear market
if Bitcoin closes up three consecutive
months. If Bitcoin closes above $76,000
this month, the bear market is
definitely over.
And he says "A gigantic AI financing
uh is part of the reason why this boom
will continue."
>> That's his view.
>> right now?
>> $81,000.
>> So, he's basically saying it's already
over then, is what you're saying.
>> If it closes end of the month at the
current level or above $76,000, which is
May, so we have 23 days 23 days to
sustain current levels, bear market is
over.
>> Okay, so what's your question?
>> Do you agree with that view?
>> I'll start with I love Tom Lee. I've
known Tom Lee for
25 years. Um I think he covered me when
I was on the buy side tiger and he was
at JP Morgan as a telco analyst. He
covered me when I ran my own phone when
he was a strategist at JP Morgan. He's a
very smart guy. He knows statistics and
he's he can pull them out like crazy.
So, I don't want to discount his numbers
ever.
>> Sure.
>> Um
I'll tell you what I think, okay?
Roughly uh January February, I think
we're hitting a low. We're seeing a
changing of the guard. The old guard
that were the old school Bitcoin people
were selling into Michael Saylor and the
ETFs.
I think that was stabilizing back
earlier this year.
And that's part of the reason why
Bitcoin's doing better. I actually think
I don't know about the timing end of the
year, this number, that number, all that
stuff, but I do feel that there's two
things that are happening that are
helping Bitcoin be in a at least a
few months / small bull run right now.
One is you got that turning over of the
shareholders or or Bitcoin holders,
whatever you want to call it. That's
already happened. That uncertainty is
happening.
The second thing I think is important to
think about is the ability for
the RIA channel, which controls trillion
dollar trillions and trillions of
dollars of
wealth,
you know, just because they're allowed
to, when you see or in the wire houses
like Morgan Stanley said we're going to
be able to do this stuff with our wealth
channel, just because they're allowed to
doesn't mean they're going to do it
overnight. You need those individual
RIAs to get educated.
After they're educated on the product,
then they recommend it to their
clients. And that process takes four,
five, six months. And it's now in May.
So we're getting to the point where
since the beginning of the year when
these channels were allowed to start
recommending it to their individual, you
know, investors have been educated and
now the end user knows it enough. So I
think you have that flow from those
people that's also going to be helpful
in this case. So I think from those two
reasons alone,
and the fact that I think the macro
environment is calm and pretty good,
and there's still the hope of the
Clarity Act, we'll see. Those are all
reasons why I think we're going to in a
a mini good part of Bitcoin.
>> Could you elaborate on we are in a calm
situation?
>> What situation in terms of?
>> I don't know.
>> I meant like there was
>> The word calm.
>> Yeah, I meant there was big shareholder
turnover.
>> I see.
>> Now it's like, okay, the new people who
have come in, who own it, it's a new
group already. It's not, you know, a lot
of the big OG whales
are no longer or have reduced to the
point they don't need to reduce anymore.
>> Why do you say that is?
>> I mean, I think there's a couple of
reasons. Um
I think a lot of the OG people who come
in now crypto, Bitcoin specifically is
close to 18 something years old now,
right?
Um
you know, a lot of people um probably
the reason I was attracted to investing
in tech is we love innovation, the new
thing, and that's exciting.
I think when you're 18 years old and I
think crypto's going to a new phase
right now, it's no longer the new new
thing. It'll be the equivalent of asking
why there are serial entrepreneurs who
take a company from zero to one, hand it
off to someone who go from one to 10.
You're like, why don't you just go from
zero to 10? Because some people like
zero to one and some people like one to
10. So, I think there's a natural time
for some of those people, especially
given the liquidity was finally there,
too.
>> Broadridge, Broadridge Financial
Solutions, NYSE:BR, a global technology
leader that processes $8 trillion in
tokenized assets every month, is
expanding its reach into the digital
asset space and is partnering with
Avalanche.
So, tell us about the significance of
this partnership.
>> This is fantastic and is very important.
Um Broadridge is a leader in basically
in the traditional uh world of um
securities, where they uh take care of
corporate actions and they do a lot of
the stuff that people don't realize that
you need someone like Broadridge to take
care of for you, uh proxy votes and all
that stuff.
And um
they have announced, and we're very
proud to say, a deal where they're going
to do the online token on-chain
tokenized equities uh and do and put
that record on an Avalanche blockchain.
They're uh partnering with us to do
that. And very shortly, the Galaxy
equity will be one that's going to be
put into the Avalanche uh blockchain
through Broadridge. So, they do all the
corporate actions and stuff. And that's
a big part of traditional, you know,
equity. So, I think this is a huge move.
How it fits into the world that I see
and what Avalanche and Ava Labs is all
about is, you know, from talking to you
from like 6, 7 years ago, from day one
we wanted to like be both like the
crypto serve the crypto native customer,
but also we want to be a technology that
could be the default place, the default
infrastructure for all institutional
assets to come. So, we want to help
businesses. And
this what we've done is created
basically the components and the pieces.
We think of it as there's an asset layer
and then there's an infrastructure
layer. The asset layer is all the stuff
like the the billions of stable coins,
the money market and treasuries, the
private credit, private equity, the
funds, and the even public equity that's
tokenized on Avalanche.
Then, this is where Broadridge fits in.
This is the infrastructure stuff. For
all of that to happen, you know,
everyone wants to tokenize real world
assets, but they forget like you need
systems underneath that to make those
things smooth.
Obviously, there is the crypto native um
infrastructure, whether that is wallets,
on-off ramps for fiat to crypto,
custody, etc. But there's also
traditional finance things like who's
going to do corporate actions, who's
going to do all the stuff behind the
scenes that make your ownership of a
company, your proxy vote, all that stuff
smooth, compliance and regulation, and
etc. etc.
Broadridge is one of those partners and
pieces that help the infrastructure
layer of the future world of tokenized
real world assets. So, it's really a
great thing and we can't wait to
um with them.
>> I think for investors the key question
is always value capture. Um Straight X
is a Singaporean
uh company that you work with. Uh
they're building
their version of stable coins and
they're very big in Asia.
But my question is, okay, all these
companies and apps building on top of
this infrastructure,
>> Mhm.
>> who captures the value?
>> Okay, so let's go back to first part of
StraitsX.
StraitsX is a great thing. They have
their own stablecoin. Obviously, it's
Asia-oriented.
Um
they're doing it on top of Avalanche.
That goes to show you how what they
think of Ava Labs and Avalanche, okay?
So, let's start there. They're also
connected and plugged into Alipay,
GrabPay. So, they have massive
distribution. Um we're very proud to be
working with them and having them chosen
having them chose, you know, Ava Labs
Avalanche. So, that's the first part I
wanted to get out. Now, you're talking
about who's capturing value where and
how.
I mean, that's a very question. I think
a lot of Let's take Bitcoin out of the
equation, okay? Product market fit for
digital gold, if you want to call it,
okay? Some people believe, some people
don't, but that's kind of what it is
right now, okay? And it's 50% of the 2.7
trillion, whatever it is.
Everyone else, the question is where's
the value capture, right?
Um
I think there's got to be value capture
all along the chain. Ultimately, the
apps have That's the dapps, we call
them, on top. They have to be able to
run a business and have a reason
why and why it's successful. And then,
for them to to be on top of an
infrastructure, ultimately, the layer
ones also have to figure out their, call
it, token economics so that they can be
alive to service all of these
applications.
The way Avalanche is set up is it's kind
of a network of networks. You have the
main chain, but you can spin up your own
bespoke,
purpose-built
blockchain, self-sovereign blockchain.
A lot of the traditional finance people
have it in a closed, private chain and
not part of the permissionless.
But, and they're capturing value already
just because they're in their own
private chain. We capture a little bit
of value cuz they pay us like to to to
do that.
But, ultimately, they also want the
world where they can connect to the
other hundred other layer ones that are
in the Avalanche ecosystem. And then, at
some point, they want to connect to the
main chain for liquidity at
Avalanche, and it's EVM compatible, so
they can connect to the Ethereum world
and all of that stuff. So,
I think it starts with the customer has
to be able to create value for
themselves, and they are already doing
it.
And then, once they start connecting,
the natural value will flow through to
the rest of the Avalanche ecosystem as
well.
>> Okay.
>> Great answer.
>> Thank you very much. Best of luck with
the continuation of Avalanche's
evolution and success. And we'll speak
next time.
>> Thank you. Dave, pleasure.
>> John, good to see you.
>> My pleasure.
>> Thank you for watching. Don't forget to
like, subscribe.